

JOSE RODRIGO ROJO GARCIA

Mathematician and Programmer

- @ rodrojog89@gmail.com
- **J** +358466608796
- Lappeenranta, Finland



EXPERTISE

Statistical Analysis

Simulation

Numerical Analysis

Optimization

PROGRAMMING

Python Matl

Matlab |

) C++

Fortran 95

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Advanced / C1

PUBLICATIONS

Google Scholar: J. Rodrigo Rojo-Garcia

ABOUT ME

I am a mathematician with main expertise in statistics. My experience is in the development and programming of Bayesian algorithms, including topics as Monte Carlo simulation and Kalman Filters. I have applied these techniques in the field of chromatography for the chemistry industry.

My interests are programming and solving industrial or financial problems with statistical tools.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Researcher | Lappeenranta University of Technology

1 04 2021 - Present

- Lappeenranta, Finland
- Scientific research related with the statistical algorithms.
- · Assitant lecturer in mathematical courses.

Assistant Lecturer | National Autonomous University of Mexico

2015 - 2019

- Mexico City, Mexico
- · Courses of advanced mathematics (Faculty of Sciences).

Lecturer | National Autonomous University of Mexico, High-school Number 7

2017 - 2018

- Mexico City, Mexico
- Courses of mathematics at high-school level.

EDUCATION

Doctoral studies in Engineering Science | Lappeenranta University of Technology

1 04 2021 - Present

- Lappeenranta, Finland
- Major: Computational Science.
- Minor: Applied Mathematics.

M.Sc in Mathematics | National Autonomous University of Mexico

2018 - 2020

Mexico City, Mexico

B.Sc in Mathematics | National Autonomous University of Mexico

2013 - 2018

Mexico City, Mexico

B.Eng in Geophysics | National Autonomous University of Mexico

2008 - 2013

Mexico City, Mexico